Chopping is another sort of a stroke that we can use on the horse's, this one in particular you have to be careful where you are using it.
It is just what it sounds like, it's like a karate chop sort of a thing, I guess.
And you hold your hand this way, the fingers closed and you are actually striking the horse with the side of your hand.
And you can use a fair amount of pressure when you are doing this.
You really want to be careful and be paying attention to what you are doing.
Watch your horse for signs of reaction, watch your horse for flinching and be feeling with your hand while you are doing it.
Watch your horse is doing, how, what their reaction is to it.
If they start to duck away from what you are doing and you need to back off, perhaps that's an area where you should be using a different sort of a stroke.
But again you want to keep your fingers closed, use the sides of your hand and just use light moderate and heavy pressure.
And be careful where you're using that sort of a stroke.